Finding Aid for the Anne Scales Benedict Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Anne Scales Benedict Papers
1896-1951
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0039
1.05 linear_feet
Biography/History
See attached biography from Vanderbilt Alumnus Magazine (now Vanderbilt Magazine), Vol. 68 No.2 (Winter 1983), p. 14
Scope and Contents
This 1.05 linear feet collection, 4 boxes, has two series: Series I contains materials related to the activities of the Vanderbilt Alumnae Council, especially their efforts to persuade the University to hire a Dean of Women, build a women’s dormitory, and to raise money toward these ends. Series II contains materials unrelated to Vanderbilt Alumnae Council and includes some personal correspondence, ephemeral items, a Bible, pamphlets, a postcard album with 155 cards plus 5 individual postcards, and a sketchbook.
- Series I: Vanderbilt Alumnae Council
  - Correspondence – Outgoing
    - Friend, July 2, 1923 (Box 1)
    - Mr. Smith, July 16, 1923 (Box 1)
    - Mrs. A. R. Robert, July 23, 1923 (Box 1)
    - Annie Tillett, August 27, 1923 (Box 1)
    - Granbery Jackson, October 19, 1923 (Box 1)
    - Alumna, April 4, 1926 (Box 1)
    - Mr. Ruml, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Correspondence – Incoming
    - S. M. Evans, August 4, 1923 (Box 1)
    - Charlotte Gailor, March 25, 1923 (Box 1)
    - Charlotte Gailor, April 10, 1923 (Box 1)
    - Charlotte Gailor, April 20, 1923 (Box 1)
    - Charlotte Gailor, n.d. – (3) (Box 1)
    - Granbery Jackson, October 2, 1923 (Box 1)
    - James H. Kirkland, February 2, 1924 (Box 1)
    - w/attachment, April 21, 1924 (Box 1)
    - Ethel Moore, April 30, 1923 (Box 1)
    - Mrs. J. G. Porter, October 15, 1923 (Box 1)
    - B. Rumel, April 23, 1924 (Box 1)
    - Alex. H. Sands, Jr., May 7, 1926 (Box 1)
    - Frederick Unger, June 24, 1924 (Box 1)
    - Elizabeth Denny Vann, July 16, 1923 (Box 1)
    - Wolfsohn Musical Bureau, October 25, 1924 (Box 1)
    - Wolfsohn Musical Bureau, December 17, 1924 (Box 1)
    - Wolfsohn Musical Bureau, December 20, 1924 (Box 1)
    - Wolfsohn Musical Bureau, January 19, 1925 (Box 1)
  - Agreements and Contracts
    - Between Madame Margaret Matzenauer (soprano) and Vanderbilt Alumnae Council, October 14, 1924 (Box 1)
    - Between Beniamino Gigli (tenor) and Vanderbilt Alumnae Council, December 20, 1926 (Box 1)
  - Announcements and Posters
    - Announcement of Matzenauer concert, January 1925 (Box 1)
    - Announcement of Gigli concert, February 1927 (Box 1)
    - Poster announcing cabaret luncheon, June 1925 (Box 1)
  - Constitution
    - December 1923 (Box 1)
  - Fund-raising Materials
    - Poster for Anna Elizabeth Wade, with handwritten notes for pageant, 1923 (Box 1)
    - Greater Goucher Fund (Box 1)
    - Fund-raising through sale of magazine subscriptions (Box 1)
  - Lists
    - Vanderbilt Alumnae in Nashville (Box 1)
    - Telephone Committee, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Minutes
    - Mass Meeting, March 3, 1923 (Box 1)
    - Meeting, April 7, 1923 (Box 1)
    - Meeting, May 14, 1923 (Box 1)
    - Meeting, June 18, 1923 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings
    - ‘Local Chapter of AAUW Has It’s May Meeting’, May 3, 1923 (Box 1)
    - ‘Plan Pageant at Vanderbilt’ (Box 1)
    - ‘Margaret Matzenauer Best Woman Singer Here in Years’, n.d. (Box 1)
    - ‘Gigli Display Gift of Great Artist’, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Notes
    - Mrs. Benedict notes for mass meeting, March 3, 1923 (Box 1)
    - Charlotte Gailor notes on staging pageant, June 1923 (Box 1)
    - Financial report on Matzenauer concert, January 1925 (Box 1)
    - List of names for telephone committee, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Programs
    - Mme. Margaret Matzenauer, January 30, 1925 (Box 1)
    - Alumni Cabaret Luncheon, June 9, 1924 (Box 1)
    - Alumni Cabaret Luncheon, June 8, 1925 (Box 1)
    - Alumni Cabaret Luncheon, June 7, 1926 (Box 1)
  - Speeches – by Anne Scales Benedict
    - Vanderbilt University and the Education of Women (Box 1)
    - Untitled, n.d. – (2) one handwritten (Box 1)
  - Tickets to Vanderbilt Pageant
    - June 12, 1923 (Box 1)
- Series II: Personal
  - Address to the Ladies Aid Society for Student of Vanderbilt University by Chancellor J. H. Kirkland, October 1, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Constitutions
    - Nashville Chapter of the Southern Association of College Women, n.d. (Box 1)
    - Alpha of Tennessee (Phi Beta Kappa), 1933, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence – Incoming
    - From Jno T. Clary, October 4, 1907 (Box 1)
  - Ephemeral Items – From Bible Pockets
    - Annual Report – Women’s Home Mission Society, 1908-1909 (Box 1)
    - Bookmarks, undated (Box 1)
    - Church Calendar – First Baptist Church, San Diego, California (Box 1)
    - Daily Verse Circle, 1894 (Box 1)
    - Dress Purchase, 1908 (Box 1)
    - Epworth League – Devotional Meetings, 1905, 1906 (Box 1)
    - Notes, n.d. (Box 1)
    - Prayer Cards, n.d. (Box 1)
    - Visitor’s Card of Introduction, n.d. (Box 1)
    - Women’s Foreign Missionary Society Leaflets, 1897-1898 (Box 1)
    - Women’s Home Mission Society Leaflets, 1907-1909 (Box 1)
    - Women’s Missionary Society Leaflets, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Music
    - “OLD VANDY” - Song and Chorus (Words by Saidee S. Luff; Music by Emma L. Ashford), undated (Box 1)
  - Pamphlets – Civil War
    - Truth of the War Conspiracy of 1861, 1921 (Box 1)
    - Jefferson Davis – A Character Sketch (Box 1)
  - Pamphlets – Miscellaneous
    - Comfort For Those Who Mourn, 1930 (Box 1)
    - Forget-Me-Nots for the Bride, n.d. (Box 1)
    - The Friendship Book, 1934 (Box 1)
    - Hemlock Twigs and Balsam Sprigs By James Peele Parker, Black Mountain Printery, 1922 (Box 1)
    - His Comfort, 1937 (Box 1)
    - Life’s Lovely Leaves By Margaret Prentis Ramsay, Artcraft Press, 1951 (Box 1)
    - The United Nations – Action for Peace By Marie and Louis Zocca, Rutgers University Press, 1951 (Box 1)
  - Pamphlets - Nashville
    - Vanderbilt, A Tower of Strength to Nashville, [1926] (Box 1)
    - Historic Homes of the Old South by The American National Bank, Nashville, 1941 (Box 1)
    - Milestones in the History of Nashville by the American National Bank, Nashville, 1942 (Box 1)
  - Pamphlets – Travel
    - California’s Missions, 1912 (Box 1)
    - A Guide Book for Williamsburg, Virginia, 1936 (Box 1)
    - Handbook for the Exhibition Buildings of Colonial Williamsburg, 1936 (Box 1)
    - London Visitor (Box 1)
    - Rebuilding the Temple By Rev. Leslie D. Weatherhead, 1941 (Box 1)
    - Syrian Protestant College – Beirut, Syria, 1896 (Box 1)
  - Programs
    - Nashville Chapter of the Southern Association of College Women, undated (Box 1)
      - The Redirection of Education for Girls, 1911-1912 (Box 1)
      - A Study of Nashville, 1912-1913 (Box 1)
      - Women in Society, 1914-1915 (Box 1)
    - Yearbook of City Panhellenic Association of Nashville, undated (Box 1)
      - Vocations for Women, 1916-1917 (Box 1)
    - American Association of University Women – Nashville Branch, 1924-1925 (Box 1)
    - From a Japanese Garden, n.d. (Box 1)
    - Bible, Engraved (Ephemeral items in front/back pockets moved to Series III-Box #1), undated (Box 2)
  - Postcard Album - Travel
    - 155 cards, undated (Box 3)
  - Postcards – Individual – Travel
    - 4 cards, undated (Box 3)
    - 1 card cover – Westminister Hotel, Chester, England, undated (Box 3)
  - Sketch Book – Botany Class, 1905